Josh Woodcock // Full-Stack Software Engineer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w0 // j0w0.com // linkedin.com/in/j0w0

Full-Stack Software Engineer specializing in front-end development, experienced in building websites and web application user interfaces that improve efficiency and automate processes.

Technologies: React, Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Git, Jira, CI/CD and cloud-based deployment services (AWS, Netlify, Vercel, Heroku), REST APIs (Google Maps, YouTube, Vimeo, Stripe payment processing, SendGrid and Twilio communication suites), GraphQL, Firebase, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PHP, Wordpress. My web development portfolio is available on my website and code samples are available on my GitHub.

Experience

Front-End Software Developer

Visit Widget | March 2023-Present | Austin, Texas

• Develop features and enhancements for the Visit Widget platform and client websites.

Full-Stack Developer

Hahn | Contract | May 2022-December 2022 | Austin, Texas

- Overhauled legacy Learning Management System by developing a new system with React and Wordpress, resulting in quicker and more intuitive content entry, member usability, and a decrease in loading times.
- Develop, implement, and maintain new features for client websites, apps, and content management systems.
- Tech stack used includes React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and SCSS, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress.

Front-End Software Engineer

Music Audience Exchange (MAX) | January 2021–May 2022 | Austin, Texas

- Developed front end of brand and artist web apps for streaming concerts, including real-time chat and donations.
- Simplified development process for quicker turnaround by creating standardized templates for content and layout.
- Tech stack used includes React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Styled Components, Google Firebase.

Front-End / UX Developer

Remedy Urgent Care | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined urgent care web app that helped win two stages of funding for the start-up. By leveraging open-source web technologies, e-commerce, and custom form flows, the app was easily managed, scaled, and monitored.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the scheduling process.
- Tech stack used includes JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, Twilio, Stripe, WooCommerce.

MIS Web Developer

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017-January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Architected/developed custom Wordpress theme and plugins allowing for easier management and sharing of content.
- Developed and maintained full-stack web apps in PHP and MySQL for marketing events that included customer and exhibitor registration, check in and attendance, lead tracking, and online payments via Stripe.
- Tech stack used includes HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, Twilio, Stripe.

Education

Texas State University